umb.com 2005-12-19

# UMB Bank - UMB Bank - UMB Financial Corporation Privacy Statement for Individuals

**UMB is required by federal law to provide this statement to you when your account is opened and annually. If you have contacted us previously about opting out of our information sharing practices, that request is still in effect and you do not need to notify us again. If you wish to change your decision, please contact us at 800-441-9535.

OUR PROMISE. 

** UMB Financial Corporation and each of its financial institution subsidiaries (“UMB”) firmly believe that maintaining the confidentiality of our customers’ information is at the core of our customer relationships. We promise that we will protect your confidential information as set forth in this Privacy Statement. The companies listed at the end of this statement are the financial companies that are currently part of our family of companies and have adopted this statement. Our “affiliates” include all of the listed companies and any other companies related to us by common control. 

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT.** We collect and retain information about you only when we reasonably believe that the information will assist us in managing your accounts and services and in providing products, services and other opportunities to you. One of the main reasons we collect information is to protect your account and to identify you when we conduct transactions with you. The information we collect will also be used to comply with certain laws and regulations that may apply to us and to help us understand your financial needs as we design or improve our products and services. We will also use your information to administer your account and transactions and to provide you with products and services that will best assist you. We collect nonpublic personal information about you from the following sources:

  * Information we receive from you on an application or other form; 
  * Information about your transactions with us, other banks or companies in the UMB family of companies or others; 
  * Information we receive from a credit bureau. 

Examples of nonpublic personal information include information regarding your account balance, credit card use and payment history. 

**INFORMATION WE DISCLOSE.** We understand that you expect the personal information you have entrusted to us to be handled with great care. We do not disclose any nonpublic personal information about our customers or former customers to anyone, except as necessary to provide UMB services or as otherwise permitted or required by law. Please be assured that we will NEVER provide medical information we may obtain in insurance applications to any affiliate or to any associate without a need to know.

**UMB AFFILIATES.** We are permitted by law to share information about our experiences or transactions involving you or your account with our affiliates. We may also share other information about you or your account (such as information we receive from you in applications and information from credit bureaus) with our affiliates. Our affiliates provide important services and products designed to provide you with the highest quality financial services. We may share information about you within our family of companies so we can serve you more efficiently, offer you products and services that we believe would benefit you, and to make it easier to do business with us. You may choose to instruct us not to share your information with our affiliates by “opting out” of information sharing. To opt out, call us at 1-800-441-9535, or if in Kansas City, call 816-860-5780. When you call, please provide us with your name, address, social security number and birthdate. You should also provide us with the accounts and services you have with us so that we can be sure that we have identified all of our relationships with you. You cannot “opt out” on behalf of any other customer, unless you are a joint accountholder with that person. To opt out for another joint accountholder, you must provide the joint accountholder’s name, address, social security number and birthdate. You should also provide us with all of the accounts and services that the joint accountholder has with us. Even if you opt out, we are still permitted to share information about you that relates to our experiences or transactions with you or your account.

**For Credit and Debit Card Customers** **.** If a bank or company name other than UMB appears on your credit or debit card, we will not share nonpublic personal information about you or your Account with our affiliates. 

**THIRD PARTIES.** We are also permitted by law to disclose nonpublic information about you in certain circumstances to third parties that are not part of the UMB family of companies. We do not sell or share customer information to unrelated third parties for the third parties to use for their own purposes. We do share information with companies that work for us. For example, we may share information with companies that print checks for us, mail customer statements or letters or provide data processing services. These companies are acting on our behalf when they provide these services and are obligated by contract to maintain the information they receive in a confidential manner. They are not authorized to use the information for any other purpose. We also provide information:

  * When you authorize us to release information; 
  * To credit reporting agencies; 
  * To other parties when it is necessary or helpful in completing a transaction you initiate, including other financial institutions and networks involved in processing your transactions; 
  * To comply with a law, regulation, court order or subpoena; 
  * To verify the existence of your account and general information about the condition of your account for a merchant or other financial institution; 
  * In response to an inquiry about whether a check you have written on an account will clear; 
  * To local, state and federal authorities if we believe a crime may have been committed involving your account; 
  * To our independent auditors, consultants or attorneys and to agencies that regulate us. 

We may disclose all of the information we collect as described above to companies that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other financial institutions with which we have joint marketing agreements. Those third parties contractually agree not to use the information for any other purpose.

**OUR SECURITY PROCEDURES.** One of the ways we protect your information is by limiting access to information about you to those associates who need to know that information to provide you products or services. In addition, we train our associates about the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of customer information. We take appropriate disciplinary action to enforce our associates’ privacy responsibilities. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that comply with federal standards to guard your nonpublic personal information, including the prompt disposal of all unnecessary customer information.

**EFFECTIVE DATE.** This Privacy Statement is effective May 1, 2005. We reserve the right to periodically change our statement from time to time, but will not do so without first notifying you of any change.

UMB Companies that have adopted this Privacy Statement:   
UMB Bank, n.a.   
UMB Bank Colorado , n.a.   
UMB Bank Warsaw , n.a.   
UMB National Bank of America   
UMB Scout Brokerage Services, Inc.   
UMB Scout Insurance Services, Inc.   
UMBCDC, Inc.
